Let's review.
おさらいです
So far we've learned that a linear layout can have an orientation that's
これまで リニアレイアウトは 水平にも垂直にも
horizontal or vertical.
適応できることを学びました
But now let's think about whether these views are taking full advantage of
ここではそれらのビューが スクリーン不動産を十分に活用できるかどうか
the screen real estate.
考えてみましょう
When I say real estate, I mean the available space on the screen.
ここでいう「不動産」とは スクリーン上の 利用可能スペースという意味です
For our Nexus 6 phone,
スマホ Nexus 6 の場合
say we have a vertical linear layout that has three child text views inside.
３つの子テキストビューの入った 垂直リニアレイアウトがあります
Tom, Tim and Todd.
トムとティムとトッドです
When we hold the device in portrait mode like this in our hand,
私たちがデバイスをこの様に 縦向きに持った場合
then all the text views are grouped in the top left corner of the screen.
全てのテキストビューが スクリーンの左上の角に集まっています
There's all this blank space left unused.
残りの空白が全て使われていません
Similarly, if we rotated the device to Landscape mode,
同様に デバイスを横向きに回転させると
then the text is on the top left corner and there's all this blank space left.
テキストが左上の角にあり 他は全て空白のままです
It's even more noticeable on a tablet device,
スクリーンがより大きな タブレットデバイス上では
where the screen is a lot bigger.
そのことがもっと目立ちます
We're only using a small amount of the screen real estate, and
ほんの小さなスクリーン不動産だけを 使っていることになり
the rest of it is blank.
残りは空白です
We're going to learn about how we can more equally spread out these views
これから利用可能なエリアを もっと活用するためにビューを均一に
across the screen to take up more of the available room.
スクリーンいっぱいに 分散させる方法を学んでいきます
This applies to other views as well.
これは他のビューにも同様に適用します
You can have bigger images across the screen for
あなたは快適に使うために 左上角に配置された小さなビューではなく
a better experience, instead of having them really tiny in the top left corner.
より大きな画像を スクリーンいっぱいに設置できます
Same with buttons,
ボタンもそうです
For the purposes of our example, we're going to stick with text views.
そのための例として テキストビューを扱っていきます
So let's go to the XML visualizer to figure out how we can spread out
では ビューの拡散方法を明確にするため XML ビジュアライザーに
these views.
行きましょう
So here's the code for Tom, Tim, and Todd.
これがトムとティム、トッドのコードです
I have three text views within a vertical linear layout and
垂直リニアレイアウトになっている ３つのテキストビューと
this is what they look like on the device.
デバイス上の見え方です
Now, I want to show you how you can spread out these three text views.
では これら３つのテキストビューを 分散させる方法をお見せします
So that Tom is up here.
トムは上のこちら
Tim is here.
ティムはここ
And Todd is down here.
トッドは下のここです
Clearly, setting height for wrap_content is not doing the job.
明らかに「 wrap_content 」の height （高さ）の設定ではうまくいってません
The other thing we learned is to set a fixed dp value for the height.
以前に学びましたが 任意の dp 値を この height に設定します
So I'm going to set the height to be, for example, 200dp.
では 私は height を 仮に200 dp に設定していきます
Cool. So that left a lot more space for Tom.
いいですね これでトムの所により空間ができました
If I do the same for the other TextViews,
同じことを他のテキストビューにも行うと
then they also spread out more evenly across the screen.
同じようにスクリーンいっぱいに 拡散しましたね
But this solution will only work for the sides of a device.
しかし この方法はデバイスの こちらのサイドのみに働きます
If I have a tablet like I showed you earlier, then these views are still
以前にお見せしたようなタブレットだと これらのビューは
going to be grouped in somewhat of the top left corner.
依然として左上隅に 片寄ってしまうことになります
The other option for setting height is match parent which we learned earlier.
他に高さを設定する方法は match parentを適用させることです
When you set match parent for the Tom TextView
トム（子）テキストビューに 対応するmatch parentを設定すると
it takes the height of the whole parent which is a whole screen.
親ビューの高さは 全スクリーンサイズとなってしまいます
That pushes the other text views off the screen so you can't even see them.
それが他のテキストビューをスクリーンから 押し出して見えなくさせてしまいます
So let's not do that.
なので それはしないでください
Well now we're out of ideas because we tried wrap content for
さて どうしましょうか？
And we tried match parent.
match parentの適用も試みました
And none of those give us the right spacing across all different devices.
どちら方法でも 任意のデバイスでの 丁度良いスペースが取れません
Let's Google search for a potential solution to this problem.
この問題の解決になりそうなものを Google 検索しましょう
We're using a linear layout view group.
私たちはリニアレイアウトの ビューグループを使っています
And we want to equally space out the children views.
そして 均一のスペースを 子ビューの間に作りたい
So let's search for that.
さあ それについて検索しましょう
Okay, so there's a bunch of search results, but
OK 検索結果が出ました
let's click on this first one.
一番上をクリックしましょう
This is a link to the Stackoverflow site.
これは Stackoverflow サイトのリンクです
It's a Q&amp;A site where you can post questions and
これは質問を投稿して 他のアンドロイド開発者から
get answers from other Android developers.
答えてもらう Q&amp;A サイトです
I use it all the time when I'm stuck and I need help on a problem.
私は行き詰って 助けが必要な時 いつもここを利用しています
Often times other people will have already asked a question
同じことが既に他の人から 質問されていることが
that I'm having.
よくあります
So this question here is about how to evenly distribute buttons
ここにある質問は 「どうすればリニアレイアウトの幅に対し
across the width of a linear layout.
均一にボタンを分配できるか」です
This is similar to what we're looking for,
これは私たちの探しているものに似ています
except instead of buttons we're working with text views.
しかし 私たちが努力しているのは ボタンの代わりにテキストビューを
And instead of the width of the linear layout we're trying to spread it across
リニアレイアウトの幅ではなく 高さに対して
the height of the linear layout.
拡散させることです
We can read through the question or we can skim it.
ここではその質問に目を通したり 拾い読みができます
Usually I just skim for the answer.
普段 私は答えを拾い読みするだけです
So this solution received 88 votes and has a green checkmark on it.
この回答は88票を獲得していますし 緑のチェックマークがついています
It talks about how you can set layout_width to 0dp and
これは 「 layout_width を 0 dp にセットして ボタンの layout_weight を
set the layout_weight for each of the buttons to be 1.
それぞれ１に設定できる方法」 について話しています
And that splits the available width equally across the buttons.
その上「等間隔でボタンを配置したい」 とのことです
You may not fully understand the answer at this point, but that's okay.
この時点では 完全に答えを 理解できないかもしれませんが 大丈夫です
One key phrase that we saw is this linear layout_weight.
ここで分かった重要な文章は 「 linear layout_weight 」です
We haven't encountered this before, but it sounds important to the answer.
初めて出会う文章ですが どうやら重要そうです
So lets copy it and Google search for
では 「 layout_weight 」について
more information Information about layout_weight.
もっと情報収集するために これをコピーしてGoogle 検索しましょう
So let's search for linear layout layout_weight.
では 「 linear layout layout_weight 」を 検索しましょう
The first result is an article for linear layout and
最初にある検索結果は リニアレイアウトに関する記事で
it's on the developer.android.com site, so let's click on it.
「 developer.android.com 」という サイトのものです　クリックしましょう
So this is an article about the Linear Layout.
リニアレイアウトについての記事が出ました
We already learned the stuff at the top about the Android orientation attribute,
この上の方にあるアンドロイドの属性については 既に学びました
but then there's new information about something called Layout Weight.
しかし レイアウトウェイトと呼ばれる 新たな情報がここにあります
There's also an example at the bottom of the screen here with some code and
また いくつかのコードと キャプチャ画像の使用例が
a screenshot.
下にあります
I could summarize all of this for
これをあなたのために まとめることもできたのですが
you, but first I want to give you a chance to read this document.
まず最初に あなたにはこの資料を 読んでいただきたいです
And try to figure it out on your own.
そして あなた自身で理解してもらいたいです
This is going to be a lot more similar to how you're going to solve problems
このコースが終了した後も 問題解決しなくてはならない
after this course is over.
似たようなことは沢山起こります
You'll look for some information online and
あなたはオンライン上で情報を見て
try to figure out how that can be used to solve your problem.
問題解決に使えるか 判断しようとするでしょう
Okay, so this is the layout that we have now on the device.
OK では これが今 デバイス上にあるレイアウトです
And this is what we want to achieve.
そして これが達成したいことです
The three texts are spread-out evenly across the height of the device.
3つのテキストが均等な高さで デバイス内に配置されている
To solve this problem,
その問題解決のために
I want you to read the Linear Layout article that we linked below.
下にリンクを貼ったので そのリニアレイアウトの記事を読んで下さい
It's perfectly normal for
その記事の内容の
you to not understand everything that's in the article.
全てを理解できないのは いたって普通のことです
Often times you just want to have some vague understanding
何度もその記事の概念について なんとなく理解したいと思うだけでも
of how the concepts in the article may be able to help you in your work.
作業の助けになるかもしれません
Then I want you to provide some ideas on how we can build this desired
そして この実行したいレイアウトを XMLで 組み立てるアイデアを
layout in XML.
いくつか提出して下さい
You don't need to provide the full XML layout code
全体の XML レイアウトコードを 提出する必要ありません
because we're going to walk through that together in the next video.
次のビデオで一緒に 作業していく予定です
But here you could write a couple sentences or
しかし 記事の中で この問題に関するだろう情報を
bullet points on how the information in the article could relate to our problem
２～３行の文章や要点にして ここに書いてください